octopustravel.com 2012-11-08

# Privacy statement » Octopus Travel - Hotel Deals & Discounts from Luxury to Cheap Hotels

This site is operated by Octopustravel.com Limited whose registered office is at Gullivers House, 27 Goswell Road, London, EC1M 7GT, United Kingdom ("Octopus Travel" or "we"). Octopus Travel is the data controller in respect of the personal information obtained from you in the course of your use of the site and/or making a booking.

The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this web site:

### Information collection and use

We will require some personal information such as your :

a) Name;  
b) E-mail address;  
c) Mailing address;  
d) Telephone number;  
e) Credit/debit card details; and  
f) Billing address.  

We use this information in order to reserve the required services, to send you details and confirmation of such services, and, if necessary, to inform you of updates or changes to your travel plans. If we have trouble processing a request this contact information is used to get in touch with you. We would use your telephone number only if we needed to contact you urgently or if you had made a mistake entering your details. The financial information is used for billing purposes and to complete your orders.

We may also use your contact details to inform you of our products and services, including special offers that, we think may be of interest to you. If you do not want us to use your contact information in this way, please let us know in an email to [customercare@octopustravel.com](mailto:customercare@octopustravel.com). We do not pass details of your personal information to third parties except as described below.

We store your information for as long as we need to do so in order to process your order, fulfil our legal obligations or in order to keep you informed of our products. We use your information to create generic information, which we then use for market and commercial analysis. This generic information does not identify you personally.

### Sharing Information

We may share your personal information in a manner described below with (a) any member of our group, (b) our bank, and (c) involved third parties.

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

When you are paying by credit or by debit card we pass your card details to our bank for authorisation of the transaction and processing of the payment.

We may disclose your information to hotels and other providers of products and services we offer, who may use your information in the ways described above in this privacy statement. We will provide only the information necessary to ensure successful fulfilment of your travel arrangements. You should be aware that the hotels and other providers of products and services may be not subject to data protection laws.

We may disclose your information to companies and individuals we employ or contract with to perform various functions necessary for carrying out and developing our business including, but not limited to data analysis and processing, delivery and management of marketing communications, payment processing, and other related customer and support services. Such companies and individuals may be located outside the European Economic Area.

In addition, we may disclose your personal information to third parties (i) in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets; or (ii) if Octopus Travel or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party; or (iii) if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our Booking Terms and Conditions or Site Terms, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Octopus Travel, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations, including but not limited to credit reference and fraud prevention agencies, for the purposes of fraud prevention and/or investigation and credit risk reduction. Such third parties may keep a record of your personal information.

Apart from sharing your information as mentioned above, we do not disclose your details to any other person without your consent unless there is an emergency situation that requires it or we are legally required to do so.

### Log Files

We use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server and to analyse trends/administer the site/track user's movement for our internal site traffic statistics.

### Where We Store Your Personal Data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payments and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal information, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy statement.

### Cookies

We use cookies to monitor which parts of the site are most interesting to you - a cookie is a piece of data stored on your hard drive and usage is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information whilst on our site.

The types of cookies we use are described as follows:

_Session Cookies_

Session cookies are required for the site to function and do not identify you personally.  
We use session cookies in connection with specific information pertaining to your visit to our site. These cookies will expire when you finish the session. No information is stored once the session has finished.

_Permanent Cookies_

Permanent cookies remain on your computer for a given amount of time after you have left our site depending on the cookie, this could be from minutes to years. Each return visit to the site will restart the length of the time that we store the information.

Permanent cookies may also enable us to recognise you and help us improve your experience of using this site and aid in the sites functionality, for example remembering search criteria, or hotels marked as favourites.  
These cookies do not contain any of your personal information such as name, address, email or telephone number. Instead, these cookies assign and recognise you by a unique number.

_Third Party_

We allow other companies, called "third-party ad servers" or "ad networks", to serve advertisements on our behalf. We do not provide any personally identifiable customer information to these advertisers or third-party websites, except as described in 'Sharing Information' section above.

This Privacy Statement not cover the use of cookies and other tracking devices by third parties. This will be covered by that third party’s privacy policy usually found on that third party’s company website.

_Opting Out of Cookies /Clearing Cookies / Configuring Your Internet Browser_

You can configure your internet browser so that it can reject both “permanent” and “third party” cookies. Please refer to the internet browser manufacturer’s own website for further information about how to do this.

You can also clear your cookies via the browser setting, this will clear all the cookies you select to be removed.

Please note with all these options, that such action is likely to hinder performance and negatively impact your experience of this site and you will not be able to book hotels and or products or services offered by this site.

If you have any questions about our use of cookies, please email us at our customer care and we will do our best to assist you with your query: [customercare@octopustravel.com](mailto:customercare@octopustravel.com).

### Links

This site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites - this privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this site. Please check the privacy policies of these sites before you submit any personal data to them. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.

### Security

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. We use Secure Socket Layers (SSL) to ensure the privacy of the information provided to us and at no time are your debit/credit card details transmitted unencrypted over the Internet. To further protect the information you share with us we have an exhaustive security system that includes world class firewall technologies; logical network segmentation to allow restricted access to stored profile information and logical and physical security restrictions to our databases and systems. Whilst SSL encryption is used to protect sensitive information online we also take all reasonable steps to protect user-information off-line. All your information is restricted in our offices and only employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information. All employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices.

### Changes to our Privacy Statement

By using this site and booking with us you agree that our privacy statement, current at the time of your most recent booking, and it shall apply to all your information, whether given to us at the time of that booking or at the time of earlier bookings.

If we change the substance of this Privacy Statement, such changes will be included in its future version and announced through a prominent notice on this site so that you will know what information we gather, how we used that information and to whom we may disclose it.

### Contacting us

In using the Octopus Travel site, you consent to the collection and use of your personal information in the ways described above. If you have any questions or comments about this privacy statement, the practices of this site or your dealings with the site please email us at [customercare@octopustravel.com](mailto:customercare@octopustravel.com)
